<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jiaxuan Li</title>
    <description>This is the homepage of Jiaxuan Li. &lt;br&gt; Enjoy galaxies, cosmology and supernovae! 
</description>
    <link>https://astrojacobli.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://astrojacobli.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2019 18:41:09 -0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2019 18:41:09 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.5</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>astro-ph Reading in 2019</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;astro-ph-reading-list-in-2019&quot;&gt;Astro-ph Reading List in 2019&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel very ashamed for the decadence in the past year 2018. I will try to read as many paper as possible and do my best in 2019.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;011419---012119&quot;&gt;01/14/19 - 01/21/19&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sdss-iv-manga-inside-out-vs-outside-in-quenching-in-different-local-environments&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1901.05126&quot;&gt;SDSS-IV MaNGA: Inside-out vs. outside-in quenching in different local environments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-massive-survey---xii-connecting-stellar-populations-of-early-type-galaxies-to-kinematics-and-environment-by-jenny-greene&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1901.01271&quot;&gt;The MASSIVE Survey - XII Connecting Stellar Populations of Early-Type Galaxies to Kinematics and Environment, by Jenny Greene&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-mass-dependent-slope-of-the-galaxy-size-mass-relation-out-to-z3-further-evidence-for-a-direct-relation-between-median-galaxy-size-and-median-halo-mass-by-pieter-van-dokkum-group&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1901.05014v1&quot;&gt;A mass-dependent slope of the galaxy size-mass relation out to z~3: further evidence for a direct relation between median galaxy size and median halo mass, by Pieter van Dokkum group&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Continued from the following paper, which says &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;r_{80}&lt;/script&gt; may be related to galaxy halo. This paper studies this further and gets some interesting results. After reading this paper, I feel intensively that good science is linking difference fields. Dirac linked analytical mechanics (Poisson brackets) with quantum phenomena, then quantum mechanics was born. This paper superficially links the stellar mass - &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;r_{80}&lt;/script&gt; size diagram with the well-known stellar mass - halo mass relation, and get some interesting (maybe wrong, maybe correct) results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1901.05017v1&quot;&gt;Miller et al. 2019&lt;/a&gt; already shows that the stellar mass - &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;r_{80}&lt;/script&gt; size diagram cannot tell the SF and passive galaxies apart. Fig. 1 shows that the median lines of stellar mass - &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;r_{80}&lt;/script&gt; size diagram are like two pieces of power law. Then they fit this ‘broken power law’ and define the pivot mass &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;M_{p}&lt;/script&gt;, where the line turns up a little bit.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then they find the pivot mass evolve with redshift significantly. The first slope (which is lower) changes slightly over redshift, but the second slope changes much. Actually the first slope (piece) is just composed of the passive galaxy branch, and the second slope (piece) is presented by SF galaxies.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Most interestingly, they remind of the stellar mass - halo mass relation. If the x-axis is stellar mass and y-axis is halo mass, the SMHM relation resembles this stellar mass - size diagram in &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;r_{80}&lt;/script&gt;. So what’s the physics behind this? First, the halo mass is proportional to the cubed virial radius &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;R_{vir}&lt;/script&gt;. And if &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;r_{80}&lt;/script&gt; is proportional to &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;R_{vir}&lt;/script&gt;, then it’s reasonable that &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;r_{80}&lt;/script&gt; is a proxy of halo mass. So they just fit this coefficient for the most nearby redshift bin and find &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;r_{80} = 0.047 R_{vir}&lt;/script&gt;. Assuming this holds for all redshift ranges, they plot SMHM relation predicted by &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;r_{80}&lt;/script&gt;, which is now a proxy of halo mass. They find it’s good to &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;z\sim 2&lt;/script&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In measuring the SMHM relation, there are many methods such as g-g lensing and clustering (which is more direct and more observational), abundance matching, and halo occupation distribution. But different methods gives different results and have different detection ability on redshift. They author also define a pivot masses for the SMHM relations and study their evolution. They don’t match with stellar mass - size one. So they suspect the intrinsic scatter may cause huge caveat when convert a halo-to-stellar relation to stellar-to-halo relation.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-new-view-of-the-size-mass-distribution-of-galaxies-using-r_20-and-r_80-instead-of-r_50-by-pieter-van-dokkum-group&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1901.05017v1&quot;&gt;A New View of the Size-Mass Distribution of Galaxies: Using &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;r_{20}&lt;/script&gt; and &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;r_{80}&lt;/script&gt; instead of &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;r_{50}&lt;/script&gt;, by Pieter van Dokkum group&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The classfication of galaxies can not only based on stellar mass - color diagram (also stellar mass - SFR diagram), bust also based on stellar mass - size diagram. In the past, people usually use the effective radius &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;r_{50}&lt;/script&gt; as a proxy of galaxy size. (But I have been suspecting how well can &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;r_{50}&lt;/script&gt; describe the size of a galaxy for a long time.) As a common sense, massive elliptical galaxies are more extended in the outskirts, but spirals are not. If we fit a galaxy using a single Sersic model, ellipticals tend to have larger Sersic index &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;n&lt;/script&gt;. In this paper, Pieter and his collaborators check what would happen if we use &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;r_{20}&lt;/script&gt; and &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;r_{80}&lt;/script&gt; as proxies of galaxy sizes. And I remember that Sandy Faber talked about this quite a lot in a colloquium in KIAA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This paper is quite straightforward. (But I didn’t dig deep into the sample selection part.) They find that if we use &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;r_{20}&lt;/script&gt;, then using the stellar mass - size diagram can easily distinguish star-forming and passive galaxies apart. But using &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;r_{80}&lt;/script&gt;, SF and passive behaves similarly.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In this paper, authors use some new algorithms/terms in statistics: &lt;a href=&quot;https://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/diptest/&quot;&gt;Hartigan’s dip test&lt;/a&gt;; Gaussian mixture models; Bayesian information criterion; Ashman’s &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;D&lt;/script&gt; parameter; Kolmogorov-Smirnov test. But actually these are also straightforward.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They suspect &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;r_{20}&lt;/script&gt; has something to do with star-forming / quenching. Since &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;r_{80}&lt;/script&gt; is not very different between SF and passive galaxies, it may be related to the galaxy halo.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Besides, I find that log-normal distribution is interesting, see this paper &lt;a href=&quot;https://academic.oup.com/bioscience/article/51/5/341/243981&quot;&gt;Log-normal distributions across the science: keys and clues&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;still-missing-dark-matter-kcwi-high-resolution-stellar-kinematics-of-ngc1052-df2-by-pieter-van-dokkum-group&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1901.03711v1&quot;&gt;Still Missing Dark Matter: KCWI High-Resolution Stellar Kinematics of NGC1052-DF2, by Pieter van Dokkum group&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On how to measure the velocity dispersion directly from spectrum, I found a paper by Luis Ho in 2002: &lt;a href=&quot;http://iopscience.iop.org/article/10.1086/343840/pdf&quot;&gt;A Study of the Direct Fitting Method for Measurement of Galaxy Velocity Dispersions&lt;/a&gt;. The main idea in this paper is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In measuring velocity dispersion, it’s convenient to use &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;x = \ln(\lambda)&lt;/script&gt; scale, because &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;x' = \ln[\lambda(1+z)] = x + \ln(1+z) \approx x + z&lt;/script&gt; for &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;z\ll 1&lt;/script&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Find some spectrums of stars as templates. They don’t have any velocity dispersions (or can be ignored).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Assume the effect of velocity dispersion is Gaussian. Then, to get a dispersed spectrum, you should convolve the template with a Gaussian kernel with a given radius. Write this in maths, that is &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;T(x)]\otimes G(x, r)&lt;/script&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;But we should consider that the featureless continuum components are different between template and galaxy. So we simply add a featureless continuum which is typically a straight line with &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;x = \ln(\lambda)&lt;/script&gt; (in &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;\lambda&lt;/script&gt; domain this is an exponential continuum). Hence: &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;[T(x)\otimes G(x, r)] + C(x)&lt;/script&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To compensate other effects such as reddening difference between template and galaxy, we multiply a low-order Legendre polynomial, then get the final model spectrum. That is:
&lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;M(x) = \{[T(x)\otimes G(x, r)] + C(x)\}\sum_l P_l(x).&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Then we have several parameters, like Gaussian kernel radius, continuum straight line intercept and slope, and coefficients for every order Legendre polynomials. Note that in &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;\chi^2&lt;/script&gt;, the error term contains the measurement error of galaxy spectrum, and error of template which is typically negligible. At last, let MCMC be. The radius of Gaussian kernel should be the velocity dispersion (need a conversion).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now for the NGC1052-DF2 case, Shany make a spectrum combining spectrums of all special region. And this spectrum has been broadened. Shany uses templates from two Global Clusters, say M3 and M13. The templates here has already been broadened by velocity dispersion (Gaussian). And we know the &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;\sigma&lt;/script&gt; of two Gaussian obeys &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;\sigma_{\mathrm{star}}^2 = \sigma_{\mathrm{template}}^2 + \sigma_{\mathrm{measure}}^2&lt;/script&gt;, where &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;\sigma_{\mathrm{star}}&lt;/script&gt; is the velocity dispersion of DF2. So we can measure &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;\sigma_{\mathrm{measure}}&lt;/script&gt; by the same method as stated above, and then get the velocity dispersion of DF2 &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;\sigma_{\mathrm{star}}&lt;/script&gt;, which is &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;\sigma_{\mathrm{star}} = 8.4\pm2.1\ \mathrm{km
 s}^{-1}&lt;/script&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How to calculate the dynamical mass given the velocity dispersion? I need to figure out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Intrinsic shape or rotation axis (minor axis rotation.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kevin: it’s not necessarily weird that we detect a galaxy lacking dark matter in its central region. Given the large scatter of halo mass and halo concentration of a given stellar mass in the low-mass end, it’s probably that we just encountered a galaxy with low halo mass and low halo concentration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;araa-papers&quot;&gt;ARAA papers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Weak Lensing for Precision Cosmology, by Rachel Mandelbaum&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Connection Between Galaxies and Their Dark Matter Halos, by Risa Wechsler and Jeremy Tinker&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1901.05465&quot;&gt;The Faintest Dwarf Galaxies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1812.01428v1&quot;&gt;The Most Luminous Supernovae&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;gaussian-process&quot;&gt;Gaussian process&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://www.gaussianprocess.org/gpml/chapters/RW.pdf&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vox Charta Key: jiaxuan_li@PKU&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Convert LaTeX to html gif picture: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.codecogs.com/latex/eqneditor.php&quot;&gt;https://www.codecogs.com/latex/eqneditor.php&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2019 07:38:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://astrojacobli.github.io/blog/2019/01/astro-ph-2019</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://astrojacobli.github.io/blog/2019/01/astro-ph-2019</guid>
        
        
        <category>paper</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ARAA notes</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;araa-notes&quot;&gt;ARAA notes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel very ashamed for the decadence in the past year 2018. I will try to read as many paper as possible and do my best in 2019.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;weak-lensing-for-precision-cosmology-by-rachel-mandelbaum&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.annualreviews.org/doi/abs/10.1146/annurev-astro-081817-051928&quot;&gt;Weak Lensing for Precision Cosmology, by Rachel Mandelbaum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;moments-of-images&quot;&gt;Moments of images&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The moment of a 2-D distribution about the point &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;(c_x, c_y)&lt;/script&gt; is defined as a kind of average (this definition is straightforward):
\[M_{m, n} = \frac{\int \rho(x, y) (x-c_x)^m (y-c_y)^n \md x\md y}{\int \rho(x, y)\md x\md y}.\]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The moment can be generalized with a weighting function:
\[M_{m, n} = \frac{\int I(x, y)W(x, y)( x-c_x)^m (y-c_y)^n \md x\md y}{\int I(x, y)W(x, y)\md x\md y},\]
where &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;I(x, y)&lt;/script&gt; is the intensity map and &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;W(x, y)&lt;/script&gt; is a weighting function.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the images are discrete instead of continuous, we write the integral to summation:
\[M_{m, n} = \frac{\sum_x \sum_y I(x, y)W(x, y)( x-c_x)^m (y-c_y)^n \md x\md y}{\sum_x \sum_y  I(x, y)W(x, y)\md x\md y}.\]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The order of moment is defined as &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;m+n&lt;/script&gt;. Here after we usually assume a unity weighting function.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Zero order moment: &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;M_{0, 0} = \sum_x \sum_y I(x, y)&lt;/script&gt; is the total brightness of an image. We ignore the denominator here otherwise it will yield trivial result.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;First order moment: &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;M_{1, 0} = \frac{\sum_x \sum_y I(x, y) x}{\sum_x \sum_y I(x, y)}&lt;/script&gt; is the &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;x&lt;/script&gt; centroid of the image with an arbitrary coordinate origin. The centroid of image is &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;(M_{1, 0}, M_{0, 1})&lt;/script&gt;. Given the centroid, we can remove the origin of image to the centroid, and calculate higher order moments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;dl class=&quot;wp-caption alignright&quot; style=&quot;width: 280px&quot;&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/images/ellipse-moment.png&quot; alt=&quot;Second order moments of ellipse&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;

&lt;dd&gt;Second order moments of ellipse&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Second order moments: Here we discuss the second order moment of an ellipse with constance surface brightness &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;\mu&lt;/script&gt; (not in magnitude). Assume we have correct the coordinate origin to the center of this ellipse. The the horizontal aligned ellipse (black one in the right figure), it’s straightforward to calculate its second order moments as:
\[M_{2, 0} = \frac{1}{4}a^2,\ M_{0, 2} = \frac{1}{4}b^2,\ M_{1, 1} = 0.\]
We already see that the second order moments contain information about the shape, size and orientation of an ellipse. Then we study a non-trivial case by rotating the ellipse by &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;\theta&lt;/script&gt; (pink ellipse). We are very familiar with the coordinate transformation between &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;(x, y)&lt;/script&gt; and &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;(x', y')&lt;/script&gt;, which is written as
\[x’ = x\cos\theta - y\sin\theta,\ y’ = x\sin\theta + y\cos\theta.\]
Plug in these transformation and express &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;M_{2, 0}'&lt;/script&gt; using &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;M_{2, 0},\ M_{0, 2},\ M_{1,1}&lt;/script&gt;, also noticing the Jacobian of this transformation is unity, we have:
\[M_{2, 0}’ = \frac{1}{4}(a^2\cos^2\theta + b^2\sin^2\theta),\]
\[M_{0, 2}’ = \frac{1}{4}(a^2\sin^2\theta + b^2\cos^2\theta),\]
\[M_{1, 1}’ = \frac{1}{4}(a^2 - b^2)\sin\theta\cos\theta.\]
Then we can define a complex ellipticity which goes like
\[\widetilde{e} = \frac{M_{2, 0} - M_{0, 2} + 2i M_{1, 1}}{M_{2, 0} + M_{0, 2}}.\]
And it turns out to be
\[\widetilde{e} = \frac{1-q^2}{1+q^2}(\cos 2\theta + i\sin 2\theta),\]
where &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;q&lt;/script&gt; is the axis ratio &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;b/a&lt;/script&gt;, and &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;(1-q^2) / (1+q^2) = e&lt;/script&gt; is the ellipticity of the ellipse. Thus
\[\widetilde{e} = e_1 + i e_2 = e(\cos 2\theta + i\sin 2\theta).\]
Hence we have many combinations to express the shape (ellipticity and position angle) and size: &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;(\theta, e)&lt;/script&gt;, &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;(e_1, e_2)&lt;/script&gt;, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Higher order moments tell us the distortion and anisotropy of the image. Using higher order moments, we can estimate the PSF structure and how well does the PSF model behave.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-connection-between-galaxies-and-their-dark-matter-halos-by-risa-wechsler-and-jeremy-tinker&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.annualreviews.org/doi/abs/10.1146/annurev-astro-081817-051756&quot;&gt;The Connection Between Galaxies and Their Dark Matter Halos, by Risa Wechsler and Jeremy Tinker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-faintest-dwarf-galaxies&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1901.05465&quot;&gt;The Faintest Dwarf Galaxies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-most-luminous-supernovae&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1812.01428v1&quot;&gt;The Most Luminous Supernovae&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;gaussian-process-in-machine-learning&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gaussianprocess.org/gpml/chapters/RW.pdf&quot;&gt;Gaussian Process in Machine Learning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2019 13:38:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://astrojacobli.github.io/blog/2019/01/ARAA-notes</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://astrojacobli.github.io/blog/2019/01/ARAA-notes</guid>
        
        
        <category>paper</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>astro-ph Reading in 2018</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;astro-ph-reading-list-in-2018&quot;&gt;Astro-ph Reading List in 2018&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;120218---123118&quot;&gt;12/02/18 - 12/31/18&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;constraints-on-intragroup-stellar-mass-from-hostless-type-ia-supernovae&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://academic.oup.com/mnrasl/article/403/1/L79/1187683&quot;&gt;Constraints on intragroup stellar mass from hostless Type Ia supernovae&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;dark-energy-survey-year-1-results-detection-of-intra-cluster-light-at-redshift-zsim025&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/pdf/1812.04004.pdf&quot;&gt;DARK ENERGY SURVEY YEAR 1 RESULTS: DETECTION OF INTRA-CLUSTER LIGHT AT REDSHIFT $z\sim0.25$&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;112618---120218&quot;&gt;11/26/18 - 12/02/18&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;mapreduce&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MapReduce&quot;&gt;Mapreduce&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;starvation-as-the-primary-quenching-mechanism-in-galaxies&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1811.09283v1&quot;&gt;Starvation as the primary quenching mechanism in galaxies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;probing-planets-in-extragalactic-galaxies-using-quasar-microlensing&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1802.00049&quot;&gt;Probing Planets in Extragalactic Galaxies Using Quasar Microlensing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;crossing-the-line-active-galactic-nuclei-in-the-star-forming-region-of-the-bpt-diagram&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1811.11755v1&quot;&gt;Crossing the Line: Active Galactic Nuclei in the Star-forming region of the BPT Diagram&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;photometric-and-spectroscopic-properties-of-type-ia-supernova-2018oh-with-early-excess-emission-from-the-kepler-2-observations-by-tsinghua-univ&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1811.10056&quot;&gt;Photometric and Spectroscopic Properties of Type Ia Supernova 2018oh with Early Excess Emission from the Kepler 2 Observations&lt;/a&gt; by Tsinghua Univ.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;k2-observations-of-sn-2018oh-reveal-a-two-component-rising-light-curve-for-a-type-ia-supernova-by-ucsc&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1811.10061v1&quot;&gt;K2 Observations of SN 2018oh Reveal a Two-Component Rising Light Curve for a Type Ia Supernova&lt;/a&gt; by UCSC&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;seeing-double-asassn-18bt-exhibits-a-two-component-rise-in-the-early-time-k2-light-curve-by-carnegie&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1807.11526&quot;&gt;Seeing Double: ASASSN-18bt Exhibits a Two-Component Rise in the Early-Time K2 Light Curve&lt;/a&gt; by Carnegie&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-to-measure-galaxy-star-formation-histories-i-parametric-models&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1811.03635&quot;&gt;How to measure galaxy star-formation histories I: Parametric models&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-to-measure-galaxy-star-formation-histories-ii-nonparametric-models&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1811.03637&quot;&gt;How to measure galaxy star formation histories II: Nonparametric models&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;flexible-stellar-population-synthesis-for-python&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://dfm.io/python-fsps/current/#&quot;&gt;Flexible Stellar Population Synthesis for Python&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;prospector-python-code-for-stellar-population-inference-from-spectra-and-seds&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bd-j/prospector&quot;&gt;Prospector: Python code for Stellar Population Inference from Spectra and SEDs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;overview-of-stellar-population-synthesis&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ned.ipac.caltech.edu/level5/Sept14/Conroy/Conroy2.html&quot;&gt;OVERVIEW OF STELLAR POPULATION SYNTHESIS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-dark-matter-deficit-galaxies-in-hydrodynamical-simulations&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/pdf/1811.09070v1.pdf&quot;&gt;The dark matter deficit galaxies in hydrodynamical simulations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dwarf galaxies are really interesting, especially for its high DM content. But some DM deficient galaxies are found (like NGC1052-DF2 and DDO-50 in LITTLE-THINGS). The idea of this paper is: can we find these DM deficient galaxies in cosmological simulations?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They used Illustris and EAGLE, calculated DM ratio of satellite galaxies for &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;M_*&gt;10^9M_\odot&lt;/script&gt;. They find 2% - 5% galaxies are DMDGs.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The dark matter losses much faster than stellar mass from z=2 to z=0.1. The specific binding energy of DM is much higher than that of stars (DM is ‘hotter’ than stars). So they suggest: higher specific binding energy, higher loss of mass.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The reason of mass loss (especially DM mass loss) may be tidal disruption.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;These DMDGs are very close to the central galaxies, which supports the previous point.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If this point is correct, DMDGs are not contradict with &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;\Lambda&lt;/script&gt;CDM.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The details are quite ambiguous. They don’t say the stellar mass range of their sample, they only analyse one DMDG for Fig.2, 3, 4.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-foundation-supernova-survey-measuring-cosmological-parameters-with-supernovae-from-a-single-telescope-by-d-jones-and-ryan-foley&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1811.09286v1&quot;&gt;The Foundation Supernova Survey: Measuring Cosmological Parameters with Supernovae from a Single Telescope&lt;/a&gt; by D. Jones and Ryan Foley&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Foundation Survey is a low-z SNe survey using Pan-STARRS telescope. By combining the Foundation sample with Pan-STARRS medium deep sample (MDS) (high-z sample), we can get a sample which only composed of data from single telescope.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pan-STARRS is well calibrated. Crucial for the &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;w&lt;/script&gt; of dark energy. Selection effects of different surveys in the legacy data are quite different. This paper has better selection effect correction.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The color and luminosity of SNe depend on the properties of host galaxies.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For high-z sample, the sample is contaminated by some core-collapse SNe, since not all SNe in the sample have spec-z.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Replace the low-z sample by the Foundation sample, &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;w&lt;/script&gt; shifted about &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;1\sigma&lt;/script&gt; from previous results. The ‘green’ and ‘orange’ dots use totally different data, but the results are consistent within &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;1\sigma&lt;/script&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This result is based on &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;w&lt;/script&gt; doesn’t evolve, flat Universe, etc. If you allow &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;w&lt;/script&gt; to evolve with redshift, it will be much different. &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;w&gt;-1&lt;/script&gt; gets scalar field involved, while &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;% &lt;![CDATA[
w&lt;-1 %]]&gt;&lt;/script&gt; maybe due to MOND.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;splashback-radius-as-a-probe-of-cluster-physics-and-cosmology-talk-by-susmita-adhikari-kipac--stanford&quot;&gt;Splashback radius as a probe of Cluster physics and Cosmology, talk by Susmita Adhikari (KIPAC / Stanford)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Higher acceration rate, smaller splashback radius.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The background is expanding faster today than before. Lower z, smaller splashback radius.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;High mass, more friction, smaller splashback radius.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What would happen if we have: MOND? hot DM? if no Lambda?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The observed splashback radius (SDSS, DES) is 20% smaller than that predicted by simulations. In observation, we don’t see any redshift and magnitude dependences, but we see that in simulations. Why?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;111118---112518&quot;&gt;11/11/18 - 11/25/18&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;using-computer-vision-to-review-papers&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://vision.cornell.edu/se3/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/gestalt.pdf&quot;&gt;Using computer vision to review papers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;early-dark-energy-can-resolve-the-hubble-tension-by-tristan-smith&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1811.04083v1&quot;&gt;Early dark energy can resolve the Hubble tension&lt;/a&gt; by Tristan Smith&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;sdss-iv-manga-the-roles-of-agn-and-dynamical-processes-in-star-formation-quenching-in-nearby-disk-galaxies-by-kexin-guo&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/pdf/1811.01957.pdf&quot;&gt;SDSS-IV MaNGA: The Roles of AGN and Dynamical Processes in Star Formation Quenching in Nearby Disk Galaxies&lt;/a&gt; by Kexin Guo&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;replacing-standard-galaxy-profiles-with-mixtures-of-gaussians-by-david-hogg-and-dustin-lang&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2013PASP..125..719H&quot;&gt;Replacing Standard Galaxy Profiles with Mixtures of Gaussians&lt;/a&gt; by David Hogg and Dustin Lang&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;a-highly-consistent-framework-for-the-evolution-of-the-star-forming-main-sequence-from-z--0-6-by-josh-speagle&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2014ApJS..214...15S&quot;&gt;A Highly Consistent Framework for the Evolution of the Star-Forming “Main Sequence” from z ~ 0-6&lt;/a&gt; by Josh Speagle&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;102918---110318&quot;&gt;10/29/18 - 11/03/18&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;using-convolutional-neural-networks-to-predict-galaxy-metallicity-from-three-color-images&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1810.12913v1&quot;&gt;Using convolutional neural networks to predict galaxy metallicity from three-color images&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;revealing-environmental-dependence-of-molecular-gas-content-in-a-distant-x-ray-cluster-at-z251&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1810.10558&quot;&gt;Revealing environmental dependence of molecular gas content in a distant X-ray cluster at z=2.51&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;dissecting-the-main-sequence-agn-activity-and-bulge-growth-in-the-local-universe&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1810.10021&quot;&gt;Dissecting the Main Sequence: AGN Activity and Bulge Growth in the Local Universe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;deblending-galaxy-superpositions-with-branched-generative-adversarial-networks&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1810.10098&quot;&gt;Deblending galaxy superpositions with branched generative adversarial networks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Generative_adversarial_network&quot;&gt;GAN&lt;/a&gt; (Generative Adversarial Networks) seems very popular in Machine Learning recently. GAN used to create an artificial oil painting portrait called &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Edmond_de_Belamy&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Edmond de Belamy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://edition.cnn.com/style/article/obvious-ai-art-christies-auction-smart-creativity/index.html&quot;&gt;was auctioned by $432,500&lt;/a&gt; in October 2018.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Using GAN, two guys at UCSC deblend galaxies. They trained the network using mock blended images based on Galaxy Zoo postage stamp images. The result is quite good! The network only takes a trivial amount of time to deblend galaxies on a laptop. But this method can only deblend galaxies into two segments now. The authors are working on improving it to deblend the arbitrary number of galaxies simultaneously.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-does-a-successful-postdoctoral-fellowship-publication-record-look-like&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1810.09505v2&quot;&gt;What Does a Successful Postdoctoral Fellowship Publication Record Look Like?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This paper shows how many papers that a successful postdoc fellowship owner should have. The mean number of first author papers is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.codecogs.com/eqnedit.php?latex=6\pm2&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://latex.codecogs.com/gif.latex?6\pm2&quot; title=&quot;6\pm2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and mean of total papers is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.codecogs.com/eqnedit.php?latex=14\pm6&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://latex.codecogs.com/gif.latex?14\pm6&quot; title=&quot;14\pm6&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The full range of first author papers is 1 to 15, and for all papers ranges from 2 to 76, indicating very diverse publication patterns. This paper tells us: 道阻且长！&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-interstellar-medium-of-dwarf-galaxies-new-insights-from-machine-learning-analysis-of-emission-line-spectra&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1810.10548&quot;&gt;The interstellar medium of dwarf galaxies: new insights from Machine Learning analysis of emission line spectra&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-sami-galaxy-survey-comparing-3d-spectroscopic-observations-with-galaxies-from-cosmological-hydrodynamical-simulations&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1810.10542&quot;&gt;The SAMI Galaxy Survey: comparing 3D spectroscopic observations with galaxies from cosmological hydrodynamical simulations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The authors compared many IFU survey (SAMI, ATLAS3D, CALIFA and MASSIVE) results with many simulations (EAGLE, HYDRANGEA, MEGNETICUM). They compared galaxy sizes (R_e), galaxy ellipticities, velocity dispersion and (Velocity/dispersion). The figures are clear and fancy. I definitely need to write some codes to plot this kind of figure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-gas-fractions-of-dark-matter-haloes-hosting-simulated-l-galaxies-are-governed-by-the-feedback-history-of-their-black-holes&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1810.07696v1&quot;&gt;The gas fractions of dark matter haloes hosting simulated ∼L⋆ galaxies are governed by the feedback history of their black holes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;102218---102818&quot;&gt;10/22/18 - 10/28/18&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;a-new-era-in-the-search-for-dark-matter&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-018-0542-z&quot;&gt;A new era in the search for dark matter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;a-galaxy-lacking-dark-matter-by-dragonfly-project&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/nature25767&quot;&gt;A galaxy lacking Dark Matter&lt;/a&gt; by Dragonfly Project&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They used Dragonfly, MMT, Gemini North, HSC and Keck… In total they identified 10 GC-like objects around NGC 1052-DF2.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They measured stellar mass &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.codecogs.com/eqnedit.php?latex=M_*&amp;space;=&amp;space;2.0\times10^8&amp;space;M_\odot&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://latex.codecogs.com/gif.latex?M_*&amp;space;=&amp;space;2.0\times10^8&amp;space;M_\odot&quot; title=&quot;M_* = 2.0\times10^8 M_\odot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
and velocity dispersion 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.codecogs.com/eqnedit.php?latex=\sigma_{intr}=3.2^{&amp;plus;5.5}_{-3.2}\,\mathrm{km/s}&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://latex.codecogs.com/gif.latex?\sigma_{intr}=3.2^{&amp;plus;5.5}_{-3.2}\,\mathrm{km/s}&quot; title=&quot;\sigma_{intr}=3.2^{+5.5}_{-3.2}\,\mathrm{km/s}&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and total mass 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.codecogs.com/eqnedit.php?latex=\inline&amp;space;M_{tot}=3.4\times10^{8}&amp;space;M_\odot&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://latex.codecogs.com/gif.latex?\inline&amp;space;M_{tot}=3.4\times10^{8}&amp;space;M_\odot&quot; title=&quot;M_{tot}=3.4\times10^{8} M_\odot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. 
So dark matter ratio is very low.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dragonfly team also applied KCWI time and have got IFU for this galaxy (NGC 1052-DF2) recently. Looking forward to new results!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;current-velocity-data-on-dwarf-galaxy-ngc1052-df2-do-not-constrain-it-to-lack-dark-matter&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1804.04136v1&quot;&gt;Current velocity data on dwarf galaxy NGC1052-DF2 do not constrain it to lack dark matter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This paper uses different prior probability in MCMC and derived larger velocity dispersion than PvD’s result.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In PvD, M/L ratio is assumed to be constant (=2). But, is it reasonable?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They randomly selected 10 GCs from M31 GC population and did the same measurement. The dispersion of derived halo mass is very large.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;measured-and-found-wanting-reconciling-mass-estimates-of-ultra-diffuse-galaxies&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1804.04139&quot;&gt;Measured and found wanting: reconciling mass-estimates of ultra-diffuse galaxies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Fornax dSph, is a dwarf galaxy that has many red-giant star radial velocities measurement. So the total mass profile is well determined by these red-giant. Also, this galaxy has 5 GCs. So the authors used PvD’s method to this galaxy, and find that this galaxy can either ‘overmassive’, or ‘lacking dark matter’. The dispersion is really large.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The authors claimed that the analysis of velocity dispersion in PvD is biased. (I didn’t read it in detail)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The sample (N=10) is too small. I think this is the key point. If you can get a larger sample, you can do it better and more accurate.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It’s very hard to measure the total mass of a dwarf galaxy. Dispersions are all very large.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;does-the-galaxy-ngc1052df2-falsify-milgromian-dynamics&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-018-0429-z&quot;&gt;Does the galaxy NGC1052–DF2 falsify Milgromian dynamics?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If MOND is correct, this kind of galaxy (without dark matter) can be explained if this dwarf is very closed to a giant galaxy. Actually, the separation is 113 kpc and the mass of host galaxy (NGC 1052) is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.codecogs.com/eqnedit.php?latex=\inline&amp;space;10^{11}&amp;space;M_\odot&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://latex.codecogs.com/gif.latex?\inline&amp;space;10^{11}&amp;space;M_\odot&quot; title=&quot;10^{11} M_\odot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.
From the calculation, under this circumstance, MOND gives &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.codecogs.com/eqnedit.php?latex=\inline&amp;space;\sigma_{intr}\sim15\,\mathrm{km/s}&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://latex.codecogs.com/gif.latex?\inline&amp;space;\sigma_{intr}\sim15\,\mathrm{km/s}&quot; title=&quot;\sigma_{intr}\sim15\,\mathrm{km/s}&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which is only 2 sigma away from PvD’s result.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-morphology-of-hα-emission-in-califa-galaxies&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1810.08340&quot;&gt;The Morphology of Hα emission in CALIFA galaxies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This paper is quite relevant to my previous work on MaNGA H-alpha ring galaxies.&lt;/strong&gt; The morphology under emission lines can tell us some interesting things on both galaxy itself and the evolution. But this paper doesn’t tell much about the physics of galaxies.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Using CALIFA and Pipe3D, they classified 86 galaxies into CL (central Ha peak, late-type), CE (central Ha peak, early-type) and EX (Ha peak is in the outside of the central region).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They defined concentration using image moments, and they plotted 1-D profile of Ha flux.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They suggested EX objects are more evolved than CL galaxies. Their mean ages and metallicities are smaller for CL than for EX classes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The format is bad, the plots are also ugly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;101518---102118&quot;&gt;10/15/18 - 10/21/18&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;a-deep-learning-approach-to-galaxy-cluster-x-ray-masses&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/pdf/1810.07703.pdf&quot;&gt;A Deep Learning Approach to Galaxy Cluster X-ray Masses&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;a-giant-protocluster-of-galaxies-at-redshift-57-by-linhua-jiang&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41550-018-0587-9&quot;&gt;A giant protocluster of galaxies at redshift 5.7&lt;/a&gt; by Linhua Jiang&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;barred-galaxies-in-cosmological-zoom-in-simulations-the-importance-of-feedback&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1810.07701&quot;&gt;Barred galaxies in cosmological zoom-in simulations: the importance of feedback&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/pdf/1103.6030.pdf&quot;&gt;Eris&lt;/a&gt; suite simulations are first conducted by Piero Madau and his student Javiera Guedes. It is a zoom-in cosmological simulation focusing on several MW-like galaxies.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The stellar feedback contains gas cooling; SF model; SN feedback model; BH physics. Madau is an expert in gas cooling.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Eris2k has enhanced cooling, larger SF density threshold, different IMF, increased SN energy, and longer cooling shut-off time. While ErisBH includes the form of seeding, accretion, feedback, and merging of BHs. In one word, Eris2K has stronger stellar feedback than ErisBH.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bar plays a crucial role in galaxy evolution. Transferring angular momentum, star, gas, etc. In Eris2k, bar grew quickly at z~1.1, then stays in a constant state. In ErisBH, bar keeps growing. Bar lengths are also different (Eris2k &amp;gt; ErisBH).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The stronger stellar feedback in Eris2k has the effect of initially pushing the gas out of the galaxy, more effectively reducing the SF, and results, in turn, in an initial stellar mass smaller than that in ErisBH. The pushed-away gas flows back onto the main galaxy but, only when the disc is massive enough to prevent SN-driven massive gas ejections, Eris2k starts forming stars with high SF rate.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In conclusion, this study clearly highlights a link between the structural properties of bars (and of the whole discs) and the sub-resolution physics implemented in simulations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;gaia-cepheid-parallaxes-and-local-hole-relieve-h0-tension&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1810.02595&quot;&gt;GAIA Cepheid parallaxes and ‘Local Hole’ relieve H0 tension&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The author Shanks, uses another calibration standard (based on very remote quasar), compared to Riess. GAIA has a -29 \muas offset, based on quasar averaged of all sky. But Riess used a more negative offset. Note: corrected parallax  = measured parallax - offset, so Shanks got a smaller parallax, thus larger distance.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Shanks got a larger distance to many quasars, thus smaller &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.codecogs.com/eqnedit.php?latex=H_0&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://latex.codecogs.com/gif.latex?H_0&quot; title=&quot;H_0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The “local void” can cause matter outflow. Thus nearby Ia SNe all suffers from an additional outflow velocity. Shanks used his data to calculate a larger outflow velocity. After correcting this velocity, the Hubble constant gets small.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Shanks claimed these corrections don’t show anything weird in Hubble diagram. But, Hubble diagram, is very, intriguing…&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;seven-problems-with-the-claims-related-to-the-hubble-tension-in-arxiv181002595&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ucsc.voxcharta.org/2018/10/08/seven-problems-with-the-claims-related-to-the-hubble-tension-in-arxiv1810-02595/&quot;&gt;Seven Problems with the Claims Related to the Hubble Tension in arXiv:1810.02595&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s still interesting to see this kind of contemporary “Great Debate”. I think the words of Adam Riess are very reasonable, at least more reasonable than Shanks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Indeed, Cepheids’ distances measured using main sequence fitting method should not be used.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Saturated Cepheids in GAIA should not be used, even for a simple test. They should not appear in Fig.1 of Shanks paper, for scientific rigor.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The most important thing in Shanks paper is the QSO-based parallax offset (29 \muas). But as GAIA guys said, this offset depends on color, magnitude, position in the sky. A large discrepancy was found in QSO samples. Worse, Shanks didn’t mention any uncertainty of this offset.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The ‘local hole’ is not well studied by others. “The conventional (i.e., frequentist) interpretation of a comparison where a model feature increases the total χ2 by 11.5 is that it is excluded with 3.4 σ confidence (99.99%).” Here I don’t think ‘local hole’ is a big issue. It won’t change &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.codecogs.com/eqnedit.php?latex=H_0&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://latex.codecogs.com/gif.latex?H_0&quot; title=&quot;H_0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; a lot (as Riess said, 0.3% changing for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.codecogs.com/eqnedit.php?latex=H_0&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://latex.codecogs.com/gif.latex?H_0&quot; title=&quot;H_0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;h0-tension-response-to-riess-et-al-arxiv181003526&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1810.07628&quot;&gt;H0 Tension: Response to Riess et al arXiv:1810.03526&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shanks responded to Riess for every item.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1) Unreasonable, powerless defense.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2) Actually for me, any hazardous data should not be used for a rigorous conclusion. &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;fractional distance difference is roughly constant with magnitude&lt;/code&gt;… It seems GAIA data has many problems, but at least better than Hipparcos, isn’t it?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3) &lt;em&gt;*What is photometric parallax?*&lt;/em&gt; I haven’t read Riess 2018b, but Shanks’s comments seem reasonable. Neither of them can say something certain on this offset. Actually, there is always something you don’t find out. You can ascribe any weird things to something unknown. Shanks also accused the circularity of Riess.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4) Do you believe the systematics of the offset = 1 \muas? I don’t believe.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;5) This part doesn’t tell you anything. But Shanks is right, Riess cannot be too confident that GAIA DR2 confirm previous P-L relations.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;6) This part is interesting. Allowing \Omega_m changing is good and reasonable.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;7) Actually I don’t think the effect of local hole matters. The standard deviation of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.codecogs.com/eqnedit.php?latex=H_0&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://latex.codecogs.com/gif.latex?H_0&quot; title=&quot;H_0&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.codecogs.com/eqnedit.php?latex=\Omega_m&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://latex.codecogs.com/gif.latex?\Omega_m&quot; title=&quot;\Omega_m&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is larger than this effect.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From my perspective:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Right: GAIA DR2 cannot assure that Riess’s P-L relation is accurate.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wrong: GAIA parallax offset cannot simply be -29 \muas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;101318-weekend-reading&quot;&gt;10/13/18: Weekend Reading&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;des-y1-cosmology&quot;&gt;DES Y1 Cosmology:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• Dark Energy Survey Year 1 Results: Cross-correlation between DES Y1 galaxy weak lensing and SPT+Planck CMB weak lensing: https://arxiv.org/abs/1810.02441&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• Dark Energy Survey Year 1 Results: Constraints on Extended Cosmological Models from Galaxy Clustering and Weak Lensing: https://arxiv.org/abs/1810.02499&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://astrojacobli.github.io/astro-ph/des_cosmology_guide.png&quot; alt=&quot;DES cosmology&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More things on lensing should be learned!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;agn-evolution-from-a-galaxy-evolution-viewpoint&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/pdf/1411.3719.pdf&quot;&gt;AGN EVOLUTION FROM A GALAXY EVOLUTION VIEWPOINT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By Simon Lilly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;agn-evolution-from-galaxy-evolution-viewpoint---ii&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/pdf/1810.04170.pdf&quot;&gt;AGN EVOLUTION FROM GALAXY EVOLUTION VIEWPOINT - II&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By Simon Lilly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;planck-2018-results-vi-cosmological-parameters&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1807.06209&quot;&gt;Planck 2018 results. VI. Cosmological parameters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Planck parameters paper from this year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;planck-intermediate-results-li-features-in-the-cosmic-microwave-background-temperature-power-spectrum-and-shifts-in-cosmological-parameters&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1608.02487&quot;&gt;Planck intermediate results. LI. Features in the cosmic microwave background temperature power spectrum and shifts in cosmological parameters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Internal consistency in the Planck data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-des-y1-catalogs-are-here-including-the-shape-catalogs-for-cosmology-analysis&quot;&gt;[The DES Y1 catalogs are here, including the shape catalogs for cosmology analysis](&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://des.ncsa.illinois.edu/releases/y1a1)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;lsst-dark-energy-school&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lsst-desc.org/DEschool&quot;&gt;LSST Dark Energy School&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;100718&quot;&gt;10/07/18&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-physics-of-galaxy-cluster-outskirts-review-paper-to-read&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1810.00890v1&quot;&gt;The physics of galaxy cluster outskirts&lt;/a&gt;: Review paper, &lt;strong&gt;To Read&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;100418&quot;&gt;10/04/18&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;mosfire-spectroscopy-of-quiescent-galaxies-at-15--z--25-ii---star-formation-histories-and-galaxy-quenching-to-read&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ucsc.voxcharta.org/2018/10/01/mosfire-spectroscopy-of-quiescent-galaxies-at-1-5-z-2-5-ii-star-formation-histories-and-galaxy-quenching/&quot;&gt;MOSFIRE Spectroscopy of Quiescent Galaxies at 1.5 &amp;lt; z &amp;lt; 2.5. II - Star Formation Histories and Galaxy Quenching&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strong&gt;To Read&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;100118&quot;&gt;10/01/18&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-missing-light-of-the-hubble-ultra-deep-field&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1810.00002&quot;&gt;The missing light of the Hubble Ultra Deep Field&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Better reduction of HUDF region for low-surface brightness features. “I am not a big fan of the “NoiseChisel” method, but it looks like they have done a careful job.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;092418&quot;&gt;09/24/18&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;first-resolution-of-microlensed-images-to-read&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pku.voxcharta.org/2018/09/24/first-resolution-of-microlensed-images/&quot;&gt;First Resolution of Microlensed Images&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strong&gt;To Read&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vox Charta Key: jiaxuan_li@PKU&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Convert LaTeX to html gif picture: https://www.codecogs.com/latex/eqneditor.php&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 03:38:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://astrojacobli.github.io/blog/2018/12/astro-ph-2018</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://astrojacobli.github.io/blog/2018/12/astro-ph-2018</guid>
        
        
        <category>paper</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Writing</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;latex-templates&quot;&gt;LaTex templates&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://journals.aas.org/aastex-package-for-manuscript-preparation/&quot;&gt;AASTeX&lt;/a&gt;: templates for ApJ, ApJL and ApJS. Note that ApJL has a limitation for the number of figures. Check the overleaf version here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.overleaf.com/latex/templates/aastex-template-for-submissions-to-the-astrophysical-journal/bpkjwktvsqwp&quot;&gt;AASTeX Template for submissions to AAS Journals &lt;/a&gt;. Personally I prefer AAS templates than MNRAS one.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.overleaf.com/latex/templates/monthly-notices-of-the-royal-astronomical-society-mnras-latex-template-and-guide-for-authors/kqnjzrwjwjth&quot;&gt;MNRAS&lt;/a&gt;: template for MNRAS. Alexie likes this template.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Curriculum Vitae: I recommend this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.overleaf.com/latex/templates/cv-for-freshers/jkpwvnrdrxpm&quot;&gt;template&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Template for book: I highly recommend &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.overleaf.com/latex/templates/the-legrand-orange-book-template-english/jtctyfmnpppc&quot;&gt;Legrand Orange Book Template&lt;/a&gt;. I wrote a book using this template for the astronomy olympiad training last year.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For Chinese templates, check &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.latexstudio.net&quot;&gt;LaTex开源小屋&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;LaTeX is also very convenient for taking notes on physics classes. Check my notes on Statistical Physics &lt;a href=&quot;https://astrojacobli.github.io/Docs/LaTeX/NotesTemplate.zip&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. (You can compile the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.tex&lt;/code&gt; file succesfully by putting &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.tex&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.png&lt;/code&gt; in the same folder.)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;books-on-writing&quot;&gt;Books on writing&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Elements_of_Style&quot;&gt;The elements of style&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Writing-Well-Classic-Guide-Nonfiction/dp/0060891548&quot;&gt;On writing well&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.python.org/dev/peps/pep-0008/&quot;&gt;PEP8: Style Guide for Python Code&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;toefl&quot;&gt;TOEFL&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;day-1&quot;&gt;Day 1&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Foul, obstruct, accord, immutable, Sturdy, impel, compel, copious, consensual, consent, edifice, groom, infest, nomad, unprecedented, notorious, sheer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;day-2&quot;&gt;Day 2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pavilion, Ductile, epidemic, haunt, spontaneous, instantaneous, simultaneous, paddle, pedal, petal, sepal, puddle, venom, aliment, ailment, lush, fourish, malnourish, assimilate, congest, converse, corrosive gas, credential, credible, detergent, evacuation, engrave imprint, lament(悲叹)/mourn/eulogy, Substantiate, allegiance, carp (鲤鱼), catfish (鲶鱼), goldfish, salmon (鲑鱼，三文鱼), tuna (金枪鱼), sardines (沙丁鱼), cod (鳕鱼), Cornerstone, Crow, seagull, ogle, eagle, finch, woodpecker, Fire extinguisher, evacuation map, grout, Eligible, Impromptu music, Inconspicuous, Palate, soft palate/velar consonant, pinnipeds, seal, sea lion, walrus, nerve sheath tumor, tenant, landlord, tenement/slum, avenue, boulevard, Eliminate, diminish, vanish, irritated, chronic, exasperated/irritated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;day3&quot;&gt;Day3&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;adorn/ornament/varnish/furbish, debris, entitle, gospel, hamper/hinder/obscure/obstacle/stunt/thwart, sewage/drain/sewerage/drainage/ooze/silt/clog/receptacle, laureate/eminent/eminem/preeminent/prominent/distinguished, reckless/crude oil, piano recital/soprano/alto/tenor/baritone, treadmill/scuba/avalanche, scramble/crawl/creep, listless, thorn/throne, auction/patent/petition, complacence/amenity, concord/harmonious/congruous/congruity/incongruity/incompatible, trepidation/intrepid, wither/wilt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;delicatessen, dairy, pasture (is the sub-unit of a ranch), ranch, meadow, hen house, hive, bovine, cowshed, enclosure, fodder corn, silo, barn, graze, fallow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enoki/oyster/shiitake/cultivated mushroom, truffle, wood ear, kelp, seaweed, nori, scallion, leeks, celery cabbage, bulb, rib, bundle, as’paragus, fiddlehead fern, spear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yuletide, nativity of Jesus, feast宗教节日, winter solstice, carols圣诞颂歌，&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/49321138/galsim-galaxy-simulation-with-local-wcs-psf&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 22 Dec 2018 06:40:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://astrojacobli.github.io/blog/2018/12/Writing</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://astrojacobli.github.io/blog/2018/12/Writing</guid>
        
        
        <category>Astrophysics</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Statistics and Python</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;gaussian-process&quot;&gt;Gaussian Process&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gaussianprocess.org/gpml/chapters/RW.pdf&quot;&gt;Gaussian Process for Machine Learning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;david-hoggs-paper-on-statistics&quot;&gt;David Hogg’s paper on Statistics&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;data-analysis-recipes-fitting-a-model-to-data&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1008.4686&quot;&gt;Data analysis recipes: Fitting a model to data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;data-analysis-recipes-probability-calculus-for-inference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1205.4446v1&quot;&gt;Data analysis recipes: Probability calculus for inference&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;useful-python-packages&quot;&gt;Useful python packages:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://healpy.readthedocs.io/en/latest/install.html&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;healpy&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: It is a package dealing with data on a sphere. It can map every direction to a pixel position, and vice versa. It can also calculate power spectrum of things like CMB. Although it’s super useful, its python documentation is really unfriendly for beginners.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://rodluger.github.io/starry/tutorials/hd189.html&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;starry&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: very cool package that can calculate light curves of transits and secondary eclipses of exoplanets, light curves of eclipsing binaries, rotational phase curves of exoplanets, light curves of planet-planet and planet-moon occultations, and more. A very cool tutorial:
https://rodluger.github.io/starry/tutorials/hd189.html.
***&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;plot-with-python&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/AstroJacobLi/astro-ph/wiki/Plot-with-Python&quot;&gt;Plot with Python&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;using-python-to-do-data-analysis&quot;&gt;Using Python to do Data Analysis&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Very good tutorial of using python and Jupiter to analyze data, by Jake VanderPlas: &lt;a href=&quot;http://jakevdp.github.io/blog/2017/03/03/reproducible-data-analysis-in-jupyter/&quot;&gt;Reproducible Data Analysis in Jupyter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Various ways to &lt;a href=&quot;https://realpython.com/python-histograms/#a-fancy-alternative-with-seaborn&quot;&gt;draw a histogram&lt;/a&gt;, with NumPy, Matplotlib, Pandas and seaborn, by Brad Solomon.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DifMYH3iuFw&quot;&gt;Introduction of PyData community, by Jake VanderPlas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;bayesian-statistics&quot;&gt;Bayesian Statistics&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;frequentism-vs-bayesianism-by-jake-vanderplas&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KhAUfqhLakw&quot;&gt;Frequentism v.s. Bayesianism, by Jake VanderPlas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;akaike-information-criterion&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Akaike_information_criterion&quot;&gt;Akaike Information Criterion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;emcee-seriously-kick-ass-mcmc-tool&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;emcee&lt;/code&gt;: Seriously Kick-Ass MCMC tool&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;emcee&lt;/code&gt; is a python module that implements a very cool MCMC sampling algorithm cample an ensemble sampler. In order to more efficiently sample the parameter space, many samplers (called walkers) run in parallel and periodically exchange states. emcee is available from this website:
http://dan.iel.fm/emcee/current/. And some examples for EMCEE: http://dfm.io/emcee/current/user/line/&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The most up-to-date documents of &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;emcee&lt;/code&gt; is https://emcee.readthedocs.io/en/latest/tutorials/line/. It’s much prettier and understandable than before. You can install newest version by clone its GitHub, then &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;pip uninstall emcee&lt;/code&gt;, and using &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;python setup.py install&lt;/code&gt; to install new version.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you google &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;emcee example&lt;/code&gt;, you can already find a lot of good tutorials and examples.  But if you need an example for complex astrophysical application, my personal recommendation is the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;prospector&lt;/code&gt; SED fitting code by Ben Johnson:  https://github.com/bd-j/prospector&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;emcee&lt;/code&gt; employs &lt;em&gt;Affine Invariant Markov chain Monte Carlo (MCMC) Ensemble sampler.&lt;/em&gt; But Metropolis-Hastings sampler and The Parallel-Tempered Ensemble Sampler (PTMCMC) can also be found in &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;emcee&lt;/code&gt;. The PTMCMC is useful if you expect your distribution to be multi-modal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Related to today’s discussion on MCMC:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;About autocorrelation time in emcee: https://emcee.readthedocs.io/en/latest/tutorials/autocorr/ In &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;emcee&lt;/code&gt; the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;autocorr.py&lt;/code&gt; deals with this, and more here on how to use it to check convergence in real application: https://emcee.readthedocs.io/en/latest/tutorials/monitor/&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;dynesty&lt;/code&gt; Dynamic Nested Sampling code is here: https://dynesty.readthedocs.io/en/latest/ ; &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;prospector&lt;/code&gt; has an example of its application here: https://github.com/bd-j/prospector/blob/master/prospect/fitting/nested.py&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;About the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;pickle&lt;/code&gt; issue, the general description of “pickleable” objects can be found here: https://docs.python.org/3/library/pickle.html#pickle-picklable  Although in real application, this can get tricky.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;About the time spent on each realization of the likelihood, if you think there might be room for improvement, I always use &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;cProfile&lt;/code&gt; to profile the time spent on each functional call.  It is very easy to use.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;corner-a-package-of-drawing-corner-diagrams-of-mcmc-and-2d-histogram&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;corner&lt;/code&gt;: A package of drawing corner diagrams of MCMC and 2d histogram.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find everything about &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;corner&lt;/code&gt; on https://corner.readthedocs.io/en/latest/. It’s very easy to use and has many options. Good tool! You can find some examples in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;SN cosmology.ipynb&lt;/code&gt;.
***&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2005AJ....129.1706F&quot;&gt;Ford 2005&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/astro-ph/0512634&quot;&gt;Ford 2005&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A mcmc tool developed by astronomers: &lt;a href=&quot;http://dfm.io/emcee/current/user/quickstart/&quot;&gt;emcee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Astrobite on &lt;a href=&quot;https://astrobites.org/2011/07/26/astrostatistics-how-to-fit-a-model-to-data/&quot;&gt;fitting (Hogg paper)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Astrobite on correlated &lt;a href=&quot;https://astrobites.org/2014/07/01/beyond-chi-squared-an-introduction-to-correlated-noise/&quot;&gt;errors&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gaussianprocess.org&quot;&gt;Gaussian Process&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://healthyalgorithms.com/tag/pymc/&quot;&gt;pymc tutorials&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jakevdp.github.io/blog/2017/03/03/reproducible-data-analysis-in-jupyter/&quot;&gt;Data analysis using Jupyter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 13:40:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://astrojacobli.github.io/blog/2018/12/Statistics-and-Python</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://astrojacobli.github.io/blog/2018/12/Statistics-and-Python</guid>
        
        
        <category>Coding</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sky Surveys</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;optical-surveys&quot;&gt;Optical Surveys&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sdss&quot;&gt;SDSS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Sloan Digital Sky Survey has created the most detailed three-dimensional maps of the Universe ever made, with deep multi-color images of one third of the sky, and spectra for more than three million astronomical objects. Learn and explore all phases and surveys—past, present, and future—of the SDSS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s just 20 years old. See &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sdss.org/press-releases/sdss20/&quot;&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/sdssurveys/status/994412430167040000?s=21&quot;&gt;The first high-z quasar of SDSS&lt;/a&gt; was observed by Xiaohui Fan and Micheal Strauss on the Thanksgiving morning, 1998.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://skyserver.sdss.org/dr14/en/home.aspx&quot;&gt;DR 14 site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://skyserver.sdss.org/dr14/en/tools/chart/navi.aspx&quot;&gt;Navigate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://skyserver.sdss.org/dr14/en/tools/search/searchhome.aspx&quot;&gt;Search&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sdss.org/dr12/tutorials/&quot;&gt;Overview of Tutorial&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://shuang-astronomy.wikia.com/wiki/SDSS_Image_Analysis&quot;&gt;SDSS Image Analysis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://wwwmpa.mpa-garching.mpg.de/SDSS/DR7/#derived&quot;&gt;MPA-JHU DR7 catalogs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;des&quot;&gt;DES&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.darkenergysurvey.org/&quot;&gt;Dark Energy Survey&lt;/a&gt; (DES) is a visible and near-infrared survey that aims to probe the dynamics of the expansion of the Universe and the growth of large-scale structure. The survey uses the 4-meter Victor M. Blanco Telescope located at Cerro Tololo Inter-American Observatory (CTIO) in Chile. It uses g, r, i, z, and Y bands. DECam has one of the widest fields of view (2.2-degree diameter) available for ground-based optical and infrared imaging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can do: &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1811.02376v1&quot;&gt;supernovae cosmology&lt;/a&gt;, BAO, galaxy cluster finder, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1708.01530&quot;&gt;weak lensing&lt;/a&gt;, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I uses &lt;a href=&quot;http://legacysurvey.org/decamls/&quot;&gt;DECaLS&lt;/a&gt; (DECam Legacy Survey). Dustin Lang made a wonderful &lt;a href=&quot;http://legacysurvey.org/viewer#IC%20968&quot;&gt;skyview map&lt;/a&gt;. Currently DES is only a photometric survey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;hsc&quot;&gt;HSC&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://hsc.mtk.nao.ac.jp/ssp/&quot;&gt;Hyper Suprime-Cam Subaru Strategic Program&lt;/a&gt; (HSC-SSP) is led by the astronomical communities of Japan and Taiwan, and Princeton University. It’s a photometric survey for 1400 square degrees using Hyper Suprime-Cam mounted on 8.2m &lt;a href=&quot;https://subarutelescope.org&quot;&gt;Subaru Telescope&lt;/a&gt;. It is now the seriously kicking-ass survey for galaxies and cosmology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main science goals contain: &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1809.09148v1&quot;&gt;weak lensing cosmology&lt;/a&gt;, high-z galaxies, general galaxy formation and evolution (like &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1811.01139v1&quot;&gt;stellar-halo connection&lt;/a&gt;), etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;redshift-surveys&quot;&gt;Redshift surveys&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ui.adsabs.harvard.edu/#abs/2012yCat..21990026H/abstract&quot;&gt;2MASS&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://ui.adsabs.harvard.edu/#abs/2010yCat..73990683J/abstract&quot;&gt;6dF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;transient-surveys&quot;&gt;Transient Surveys&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;pan-starrs&quot;&gt;Pan-STARRS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Panoramic Survey Telescope and Rapid Response System (Pan-STARRS) is a well calibrated telescope for transient surveys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;ifu-surveys&quot;&gt;IFU Surveys&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;manga-survey&quot;&gt;MaNGA survey&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current data release is v2_1_2, containing ~2700 galaxies with redshift ranges from 0 to 0.15.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sdss.org/dr13/manga/&quot;&gt;MaNGA survey overview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://dr15.sdss.org/marvin/&quot;&gt;Marvin: a tool specifically designed to visualise and analyse MaNGA data.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://data.sdss.org/sas/dr14/manga/spectro/redux/v2_1_2/drpall-v2_1_2.fits&quot;&gt;Summary information about MaNGA objects (&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;fits&lt;/code&gt; file)&lt;/a&gt;. You can search in this file whether your objects are contained in current MaNGA data release. You can also using SDSS &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;navigate&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;explore&lt;/code&gt; tool to see whether your objects are contained in MaNGA.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sdss.org/dr14/data_access/value-added-catalogs/?vac_id=manga-pipe3d-value-added-catalog-spatially-resolved-and-integrated-properties-of-galaxies&quot;&gt;MaNGA Pipe3D Value-Added-Catalogue&lt;/a&gt; by Sanchez et al. This is what I use in my research. This VAC catalog contains the physical properties and also information of gas emission lines. _Note: The SFR in this catalog is calculated by summing up H⍺ SFR of every spaxel in the FOV. So the genuine SFR must be larger. The IMF used here is Salpeter, while the most prevalent IMF is Kroupa IMF.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://data.sdss.org/sas/dr14/manga/spectro/pipe3d/v2_1_2/2.1.2/&quot;&gt;MaNGA cube files&lt;/a&gt;, if you want to study the properties of specific galaxies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sami-survey&quot;&gt;SAMI survey&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sami-survey.org&quot;&gt;SAMI survey overview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sami-survey.org/system/files/attachments/403/sami_sel_20140413_v1.9_publiclist&quot;&gt;SAMI objects list&lt;/a&gt;: can be opened with &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.txt&lt;/code&gt; using TOPCAT.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://datacentral.org.au/services/sov/&quot;&gt;SAMI single object viewer&lt;/a&gt;: better GUI than MaNGA. After finding your objects in the SAMI objects list, you can just input the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;CATID&lt;/code&gt;, then related files can be downloaded.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://datacentral.org.au/services/query/&quot;&gt;SAMI data query using SQL&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;califa-survey&quot;&gt;CALIFA survey&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://califa.caha.es&quot;&gt;CALIFA overview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.caha.es/CALIFA/public_html/?q=content/califa-3rd-data-release-searching-tool-mac-users&quot;&gt;CALIFA DR3 search tool&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://academic.oup.com/mnras/article-abstract/471/3/3727/3979019&quot;&gt;PyCASSO database: spatially resolved stellar population properties for CALIFA galaxies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2018 02:40:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://astrojacobli.github.io/blog/2018/12/sky-surveys</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://astrojacobli.github.io/blog/2018/12/sky-surveys</guid>
        
        
        <category>Astrophysics</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Miscellany</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Weber–Fechner_law&quot;&gt;Weber–Fechner law&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;XKCD style of Mathematica plot: &lt;a href=&quot;https://mathematica.stackexchange.com/questions/11350/xkcd-style-plots&quot;&gt;https://mathematica.stackexchange.com/questions/11350/xkcd-style-plots&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;XKCD style of Matplotlib (bug for line labels): &lt;a href=&quot;http://jakevdp.github.io/blog/2012/10/07/xkcd-style-plots-in-matplotlib/#The-Code:-XKCDify&quot;&gt;http://jakevdp.github.io/blog/2012/10/07/xkcd-style-plots-in-matplotlib/#The-Code:-XKCDify&lt;/a&gt;. This code must run under python2 environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good example of 2D Histogram using astroML: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.astroml.org/examples/datasets/plot_SDSS_SSPP.html&quot;&gt;http://www.astroml.org/examples/datasets/plot_SDSS_SSPP.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Convert Jupyter Notebook to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;html&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jupyter nbconvert --to html low-z-galaxy-survey.ipynb &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Convert LaTeX to html gif picture: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.codecogs.com/latex/eqneditor.php&quot;&gt;https://www.codecogs.com/latex/eqneditor.php&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mac录屏的同时录制声音：&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jianshu.com/p/a8ff665285de&quot;&gt;https://www.jianshu.com/p/a8ff665285de&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good website to check visibility for a given RA and DEC: &lt;a href=&quot;http://catserver.ing.iac.es/staralt/&quot;&gt;http://catserver.ing.iac.es/staralt/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Convert figure to data points&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;http://markummitchell.github.io/engauge-digitizer/&quot;&gt;http://markummitchell.github.io/engauge-digitizer/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-to-use-latex-in-jekyll&quot;&gt;How to use latex in jekyll?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;gem install kramdown&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Change the markdown line in _config.yml to markdown: kramdown&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And add something like&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-javascript highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;script&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;type&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;text/javascript&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;src&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;http://cdn.mathjax.org/mathjax/latest/MathJax.js?config=TeX-AMS-MML_HTMLorMML&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sr&quot;&gt;/script&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;err&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_layouts/default.html&lt;/code&gt;. Now you can simply mark any mathematics in your posts with &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;$$&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Princeton Program: &lt;a href=&quot;https://international.princeton.edu/international-students-and-scholars/International-Student-Internship-Program&quot;&gt;https://international.princeton.edu/international-students-and-scholars/International-Student-Internship-Program&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2018 05:40:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://astrojacobli.github.io/blog/2018/12/Miscellany</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://astrojacobli.github.io/blog/2018/12/Miscellany</guid>
        
        
        <category>Coding</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Scikit-learn</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;quick-start&quot;&gt;Quick Start&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;machine-learning&quot;&gt;Machine learning&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Supervised learning: Classification, Regression. (Learn the map &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;X\to y&lt;/script&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Unsupervised learning: Clustering, density estimation.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dimensionality reduction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;dl class=&quot;wp-caption alignright&quot; style=&quot;width: 500px&quot;&gt;

&lt;dt&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/images/ml_map.png&quot; alt=&quot;Scikit-learn Cheat Sheet&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;

&lt;dd&gt;Scikit-learn Cheat Sheet&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;scikit-learn&quot;&gt;Scikit-learn&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Data is constructed by the format: (n_samples, n_features)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Datasets Examples: iris, diabetes, digits, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Every &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;estimator&lt;/code&gt; class has &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.fit(X_train, y_train)&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.predict(X_test, y_test)&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Export the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;estimator&lt;/code&gt; into a file:
    &lt;div class=&quot;language-python highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kn&quot;&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nn&quot;&gt;joblib&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kn&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;jump&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;load&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;dump&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;clf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;'filename.joblib'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;clf&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;load&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;'filename.joblib'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can change the parameters of an &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;estimator&lt;/code&gt; after construct it by using &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.set_params()&lt;/code&gt; method.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In classification, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;y&lt;/code&gt; can have multi-labels (like in iris). You can use &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sklearn.preprocessing.LabelBinarizer&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sklearn.preprocessing.MultiLabelBinarizer&lt;/code&gt;, and classify using &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sklearn.multiclass.OneVsRestClassifier&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;supervised-learning-predicting-an-output-variable-from-high-dimensional-observations&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://scikit-learn.org/stable/tutorial/statistical_inference/supervised_learning.html&quot;&gt;Supervised learning: predicting an output variable from high-dimensional observations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;nearest-neighbor-classification&quot;&gt;Nearest Neighbor Classification&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;kNN (k-th nearest neighbor classification): &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sklearn.neighbors.KNeighborsClassifier&lt;/code&gt; is also an estimator.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Curse_of_dimensionality&quot;&gt;Curse of dimensionality&lt;/a&gt;: if your sample is small and dimension is high, then your sample will be very sparse. Also it’s very interesting that in high dimensions, the high-dimensional unit hypercube can be said to consist almost entirely of the “corners” of the hypercube, with almost no “middle”.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;linear-model-regression&quot;&gt;Linear model: Regression&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Linear models: &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;y = X \beta + \epsilon&lt;/script&gt;, in which &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;y&lt;/script&gt; and &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;\epsilon&lt;/script&gt; are &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;(n\times 1)&lt;/script&gt;, &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;X&lt;/script&gt; is &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;(n\times m)&lt;/script&gt; and &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;\beta&lt;/script&gt; is &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;(m\times 1)&lt;/script&gt;. Here &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;X&lt;/script&gt; is data, &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;y&lt;/script&gt; is target, &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;\beta&lt;/script&gt; is coefficients and &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;\epsilon&lt;/script&gt; is observation noise.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Linear Regression estimator: &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sklearn.linear_model.LinearRegression&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Shrinkage: &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sklearn.linear_model.Ridge&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sklearn.linear_model.Lasso&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If we use linear model to do classification, remember using ‘logistic’ or ‘sigmoid’ function: &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sklearn.linear_model.LogisticRegression&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;support-vector-machines-svms&quot;&gt;Support Vector Machines (SVMs)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;SVMs has regularization parameter &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;C&lt;/script&gt;, smaller &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;C&lt;/script&gt; means more regularization. &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sklearn.svm.SVC&lt;/code&gt; is the estimator.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Different kernels give different results.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;model-selection-and-cross-validation&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://scikit-learn.org/stable/tutorial/statistical_inference/model_selection.html&quot;&gt;Model selection and cross-validation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since an estimator has some parameters, we need to choose the best values for these parameters to get the best behavior. So we use &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;score&lt;/code&gt; and ‘cross-validation’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CV generators: &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sklearn.model_selection.KFold&lt;/code&gt; can be used as &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;kfold = KFold(n_splits=5)&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;for train, test in kfold.split(X):&lt;/code&gt;. This can generate 5 groups of training samples and test samples. Then we can calculate scores for each set.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Another way is &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sklearn.model_selection.cross_val_score(svc, X, y, cv=5, n_jobs=-1)&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Another way is grid-search the parameter space using &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sklearn.model_selection.GridSearchCV(svc, param_grid=dict(C=Cs))&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Some estimator can automatically give the best values of some parameters. For example constructing an estimator &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;estimator = sklearn.linear_model.LassoCV(cv=5)&lt;/code&gt; and fit it with data. Then we can retrieve the best parameter ‘alpha’ by &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;estimator.alpha_&lt;/code&gt;. But we should note, this may not be reliable. We’d better estimate the best parameter by ourselves.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;pca.fit_transform&lt;/code&gt; = first &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;fit&lt;/code&gt;, then &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;transform&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2018 02:18:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://astrojacobli.github.io/blog/2018/12/Scikit-learn</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://astrojacobli.github.io/blog/2018/12/Scikit-learn</guid>
        
        
        <category>coding</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>IFU Surveys</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;ifu-surveys&quot;&gt;IFU surveys&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;manga-survey&quot;&gt;MaNGA survey&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current data release is v2_1_2, containing ~2700 galaxies with 0&amp;lt;z&amp;lt;0.15.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sdss.org/dr13/manga/&quot;&gt;MaNGA survey overview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://data.sdss.org/sas/dr14/manga/spectro/redux/v2_1_2/drpall-v2_1_2.fits&quot;&gt;Summary information about MaNGA objects (&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;fits&lt;/code&gt; file)&lt;/a&gt;. You can search in this file whether your objects are contained in current MaNGA data release. You can also using SDSS &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;navigate&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;explore&lt;/code&gt; tool to see whether your objects are contained in MaNGA.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sdss.org/dr14/data_access/value-added-catalogs/?vac_id=manga-pipe3d-value-added-catalog-spatially-resolved-and-integrated-properties-of-galaxies&quot;&gt;MaNGA Pipe3D Value-Added-Catalogue&lt;/a&gt; by Sanchez et al. This is what I use in my research. This VAC catalog contains the physical properties and also information of gas emission lines. _Note: The SFR in this catalog is calculated by summing up H⍺ SFR of every spaxel in the FOV. So the genuine SFR must be larger. The IMF used here is Salpeter, while the most prevalent IMF is Kroupa IMF.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://data.sdss.org/sas/dr14/manga/spectro/pipe3d/v2_1_2/2.1.2/&quot;&gt;MaNGA cube files&lt;/a&gt;, if you want to study the properties of specific galaxies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sami-survey&quot;&gt;SAMI survey&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sami-survey.org&quot;&gt;SAMI survey overview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sami-survey.org/system/files/attachments/403/sami_sel_20140413_v1.9_publiclist&quot;&gt;SAMI objects list&lt;/a&gt;: can be opened with &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.txt&lt;/code&gt; using TOPCAT.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://datacentral.org.au/services/sov/&quot;&gt;SAMI single object viewer&lt;/a&gt;: better GUI than MaNGA. After finding your objects in the SAMI objects list, you can just input the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;CATID&lt;/code&gt;, then related files can be downloaded.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://datacentral.org.au/services/query/&quot;&gt;SAMI data query using SQL&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;califa-survey&quot;&gt;CALIFA survey&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://califa.caha.es&quot;&gt;CALIFA overview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.caha.es/CALIFA/public_html/?q=content/califa-3rd-data-release-searching-tool-mac-users&quot;&gt;CALIFA DR3 search tool&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 16:40:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://astrojacobli.github.io/blog/2018/11/IFU-surveys</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://astrojacobli.github.io/blog/2018/11/IFU-surveys</guid>
        
        
        <category>Astrophysics</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hyper Suprime-Cam Subaru Strategic Program</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;HSC data entrance: &amp;lt;a href=”https://hscdata.mtk.nao.ac.jp/hsc_ssp/”&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SQL: &amp;lt;a href=”https://hscdata.mtk.nao.ac.jp/datasearch/”&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image cutout: &amp;lt;a href=”https://hscdata.mtk.nao.ac.jp/das_quarry/dr2.1/”&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PSF model: &amp;lt;a href=”https://hscdata.mtk.nao.ac.jp/psf/6/”&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SkyMap: &amp;lt;a href=”https://hscdata.mtk.nao.ac.jp/hsc_ssp/dr2/s18a/hscMap”&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 17:40:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>https://astrojacobli.github.io/blog/2018/11/HSC</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://astrojacobli.github.io/blog/2018/11/HSC</guid>
        
        
        <category>Astrophysics</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
